Not since Gone with the Wind has there been a great romantic epic like it!
Reds is a drama, history, romance film directed by Warren Beatty.
An account of the revolutionary years of the legendary American journalist John Reed, who shared his adventurous professional life with his radical commitment to the socialist revolution
in Russia, his dream of spreading its principles among the members of the American working class, and his troubled romantic relationship with the writer Louise Bryant.
John Reed, played by Warren Beatty.
Louise Bryant, played by Diane Keaton.
Max Eastman, played by Edward Herrmann.
Grigory Zinoviev, played by Jerzy Kosiński.
Eugene O'Neill, played by Jack Nicholson.
Louis Fraina, played by Paul Sorvino.
Reds is a 1981 American epic historical drama film co-written, produced, and directed by Warren Beatty, about the life and career of John
Reed, the journalist and writer who chronicled the October Revolution in Russia in his 1919 book Ten Days That Shook the World.
Beatty stars in the lead role alongside Diane Keaton as activist Louise
Bryant and Jack Nicholson as playwright Eugene O'Neill.
The supporting cast includes Edward Herrmann, Jerzy Kosiński, Paul Sorvino,
Maureen Stapleton, Gene Hackman, Ramon Bieri, Nicolas Coster and M.
Emmet Walsh.
The film also features, as "witnesses", interviews with the 98-year-old radical educator and peace activist Scott Nearing, author Dorothy
Frooks, reporter and author George Seldes, civil liberties advocate Roger Baldwin and writer Henry Miller, among others.
George Jessel, who died shortly before the film was released, appears as one
of the contemporaries of Reed and Bryant who were interviewed.
Reds was released on December 4, 1981, to widespread critical acclaim.
Beatty was awarded the Academy Award for Best Director and the film was
nominated for Best Picture, but lost to Chariots of Fire.
Beatty, Keaton, Nicholson, and Stapleton were nominated for Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Supporting
Actor, and Best Supporting Actress, respectively, with Stapleton winning her category.
Beatty became the third person to be nominated for Academy Awards in the categories Best Director, Actor, and, with co-writer
Trevor Griffiths, Original Screenplay—losing again to Chariots of Fire—for a film nominated for Best Picture.
In June 2008, the American Film Institute revealed AFI's 10 Top 10—the best ten films in ten
"classic" American film genres—after polling over 1,500 people from the film community.
Reds came in ninth in the epic genre.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, world war i,
war correspondent, biography, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.